When you look at all the different
Bitcoin treasury companies, who is doing
it right and who is doing it for the
wrong intentions? I think as an investor
in treasury companies myself, I would
look at it that
When the money is big enough, it's a
test for all these management right.
And that's effectively what you see
monetary premium in the stock market, in
real estate, in the bond market where
arguably things are overpriced.
What is the end game? Let's say [music]
most of the companies in the world now
holds Bitcoin. Then what? And I think
that's [music] probably where it's going
because
>> [music]
>> It is such a great day because Adam Back
is back. Hello Adam. Hello Bonnie.
Today we're going to talk about
something a little different.
Uh we've met twice and we've talked
about the history of Bitcoin.
But today we want to talk about your
Bitcoin treasury company. Can you tell
us your plan? What is going on right
now? Yeah, so it's
uh Bitcoin standard treasury. We worked
with Cantor Fitzgerald to do a series of
financial raises around a SPAC. Uh the
SPAC is called Siebert. Uh that's the
ticker name. Uh Cantor Equity Partners
here.
And of course, because it's a SPAC, the
ticker is uh listed actually on the
Nasdaq and at the moment we are in a
kind of regulatory period where we wait
for regulatory approval uh for the
business combination, so the merger
between the SPAC and the new company.
And so the new company, BSTR, is what is
being proposed to merge with the SPAC.
And so uh the data between the different
raises is that we have uh 25,000
Bitcoin.
So
3 billion, maybe a bit less depending on
the Bitcoin price uh in the new company.
>> Mhm.
And then a number of raises that came
in. So the SPAC itself uh has 200
million roughly. Uh how much money you
follows through from the SPAC depends on
proportion of redemption, so that's you
know, uncertain. Um and then we did a
series of raises. So uh a dollar equity
pipe 400 million. Mhm. Um a convertible
note 500 million.
Some options on top of that,
for to do more and a convertible
preferred. So this is a bit like some of
the preferred stock that MicroStrategy
issued, so it's a convertible
one of those.
And the other thing we did which is
unique. So firstly doing a preferred
stock at the beginning is
a first. MicroStrategy took some years
to build up to that. You know, they did
the bonds and they did convertible
notes, they did ATM.
And only a few years later did they get
to start introducing preferred.
We introduced the preferred during the
raise process itself.
Um and then the last thing we did which
is actually unique as far as we're aware
in the US is to do a Bitcoin basis
uh pipe, equity pipe. What does that
>> So we it means that normally with an
equity pipe people are committing to
invest dollars, but here we had an
opportunity for Bitcoiners to invest
Bitcoin directly.
>> Oh. And so they were able to, you know,
invest using Bitcoin itself actually
into the process. And now the
interesting thing with that is
the the project is
primarily Bitcoin. So about 60 to 70% of
the money coming in is actually already
Bitcoin because 25,000 Bitcoin
in BSTR, the new company.
>> 5,000 Bitcoin in equity pipe. And if you
add it up, it's something like 2/3,
60-70%
Bitcoin as opposed to US dollar raises.
And
on the close, which is when the
regulators approve it, hopefully, you
know, perhaps in Q4 this year,
then the the the reference price for a
SPAC is $10. It's the kind of market
standard. And at that at the close, the
Bitcoin investors they divide the amount
of Bitcoin they invested by or the price
of Bitcoin by $10 and that's how many
shares they get.
So if Bitcoin price is higher, they get
more shares. If it's lower, they get
less shares. And so that means that when
they're investing with Bitcoin, they're
benefiting from the Bitcoin price
movement.
>> Mhm.
They're exposed to Bitcoin price
movement between the time they signed
agreement to invest and the time that
they actually deliver the Bitcoin and
then subsequently receive the shares.
Two questions there. Uh first is that
25,000 Bitcoins are from founding
shareholders.
>> Mhm. Is that you? It's myself and some
other investors.
>> Okay. Um you decided to put your Bitcoin
to work. This is what it is. Um
why?
Um well, actually I'd become exposed to
treasury companies some years ago when
MicroStrategy
started their treasury company
exploration. And
when they first started,
um they were explaining it as an
inflation hedge. Mhm. So they had 500
million dollars of cash.
They made a share buyback offer if
anybody didn't like the treasury
proposal. A lot of the money, the most
of the money stayed in. And then they
used most of it to buy Bitcoin. And I
thought that was, you know, an
interesting thing to do. And they
started trying to explain how they did
it to other [clears throat] public
companies.
Um but what what I didn't expect is they
didn't stop there. Mhm.
Then they borrowed money with corporate
bonds and bought more.
Later they started issuing convertible
notes to buy more and they became really
a a very rapid and aggressive buyer of
Bitcoin. And
so with that, they sort of developed
this treasury company market effectively
where people are looking at
the rate of increase in Bitcoin per
share. So I think they were sort of
trailblazing and learning. And somewhere
in that process, I thought I like
the
sort of what they're trying to propose
to the market that they're proposing to
public companies that it could be in
their financial interest as well as for
individuals to consider Bitcoin as
inflation hedge. And so I thought one
way to support what they're doing is if,
you know, a number of people in the
Bitcoin space buy MicroStrategy shares,
it'd be a form of support because, you
know, if the traditional market didn't
take a positive view of Bitcoin, their
price, you know, the support for the
company would be coming from the
Bitcoiners. So I started buying some
MicroStrategy shares. Uh later I
actually had an opportunity to meet with
and talk with Michael and the other
uh you know, at some point Michael
Saylor became the chairman. And the CFO
became the CEO and they brought in
a new CFO. So I had a chance to talk
with the different management team
uh you know, about how they saw it. And
and then later also, you know, from that
experience started investing in some of
the other treasury companies, Metaplanet
fairly early.
And um the Blockchain Group, which is
now Capital B. Invested in that in a
private placement uh last November,
which was really at the beginning of
their Bitcoin Mhm. journey. And also in
H100 and some other uh companies, some
some of the equity pipes for SPACs or
RTOs. Uh and a few more. So
I I kind of
uh you know, learned by doing. I think
it's a good way for me at least to try
to understand the economic effects and
the market effects and the metrics and
what you know, how the market perceives
them is to to invest and trade. So
that's what I did. And of course, in
doing that, I developed opinions about
you know, what could be done
differently, what could be done better.
And so ultimately
uh with some other investors started my
own treasury company, which was Bitcoin
Standard Treasury. You know, when I look
at
um strategy and what Michael Saylor is
doing, it feels like he's like this
master chef. He's putting different
ingredients, which is different
financial products into this Mhm. dish.
But
I don't understand how he gets it so
perfectly. When you
cook your dish, how do you decide what's
the perfect balance of different
financial product, if different
instruments?
Well, I mean, you can see with
MicroStrategy that um I mean, they were
quite transparent in explaining what
they were thinking as they went.
>> Mhm. And in fact, learning from some of
the things they did and adapting and
trying new things to see how the market
likes them. So there was some trial and
error and some you know, trying to
understand what the market wants or gaps
in the market. So
you know, for example, you can see with
them moving from bonds to convertible
notes, there's a
a kind of uh strategic advantage there,
which is the convertible notes
um gives you a less diluted way to raise
money because they were selling
convertible notes at some time for 50%
conversion premium. And so they could
raise 150 million buy Bitcoin today. And
you know, if if they converted, they
would only ex- the company would only
experience 100 million of dilution. So
you can see there's a 33% advantage for
dilution, so that's more effective at
increasing Bitcoin per share. And then
the other thing is once they have an
positive MVRV above one,
they can sell shares at the market and
that will also increase Bitcoin per
share. And more recently with the
perpetual products,
that you know, some of those are
convertible version and some which are
not not convertible, so they're just
paying a coupon.
So, in a way that you know, that's a
different formula. So, I think with the
preferred, it's quite interesting
because they are providing a product
like a financial instrument that's
publicly traded
that
is providing an interest rate. Mhm. And
so it's sort of competing with a fixed
income market where people are buying,
you know, perhaps trade US treasuries or
public company bonds that pay a coupon
and things like that.
And
ultimately it's sort of indirectly
collateralized by the Bitcoin they hold,
but it's
you know, so it's not giving
unless it's a convertible and they do
have a convertible one. Um
The other one, the other three are not
providing Bitcoin upside,
but they're providing attractive
interest rate return and so it's a way
for the company to
access the capital market,
provide an attractive financial product
interesting trade-off ultimately
you know,
uh enabled by the Bitcoin balance sheet
and give the company the ability to buy
more Bitcoin per share for the
shareholders. So, I think it's sort of
transforming a risk profile
and you know, of course the convertible
preferred with MicroStrategy is also
somewhat interesting because it has the
option to convert. I think it's at
$1,000 per share. Mhm. Um
and an interest rate in the meantime. Of
course, with some uh enterprise risk
component that if MicroStrategy got into
difficulty,
the the value could fall or the dividend
might not get paid. You said something
really interesting. So, you said like
some people wonder if Bitcoin treasury
companies will um reduce opportunity or
drive down the premium, but you said the
opposite.
Well, I think it's uh there is an
element of
you know, some of the instruments are
only available today from MicroStrategy
or from MicroStrategy and one other
company. And so I think if there are
more,
you know, for example, preferred
instruments in the market, that uh you
know, it provides a
sort of uh pallet of options, you know,
where companies that are investing or
individuals that are investing in these
products can look at providers from
different providers. And so I think you
get some
kind of market familiarity.
You can see that with the preferred that
MicroStrategy has issued, they are
sometimes a slow start because the
market is getting accustomed to it and
they offer them a discount.
And then once they're trading,
effectively the market tells you what
the implied
interest rate is. And so the discount is
really because it's a new product,
uh a new type of instrument effectively.
And even though it's, you know, it's an
attractive interest rate,
he would argue an attractive risk
profile, Mhm. they're still learning,
you know, the the buyers of this are not
invested in the Bitcoin ecosystem. They
don't have any particular view if
Bitcoin is going up or down or sideways.
And so it's a bit harder for them to
understand, but I think, you know, as
they look at more products, as he's able
to sell more of them, the market should
get more familiar with them. And you can
see that the last one that
MicroStrategy issued, the STRCT or
stretch as they call it,
was actually able to sell a much larger
amount of that in the initial, I think,
2.5 billion, Mhm. which is a lot much
larger initial sale than he was able to
do with the other three. When you look
at all the different from Bitcoin
treasury companies and different methods
to raise money,
do you have a judgment? Like who is
doing it right and who is it doing it
for the wrong intentions?
I think as an investor in treasury
companies myself,
I would look at it that I want to feel
that I understand the motivation of the
management. And ultimately that they can
trust them
to
um
stay on the path, right? That they're
going to
focus on Bitcoin.
They're going to use the capital raised
substantially to buy Bitcoin. They're
not going to change their mind and buy
something else or, you know, keep the
money
and not use it to buy Bitcoin, but use
it to do something else. And so, you
know, if one example of that was
GameStop. Mhm. So, GameStop
entered the market, raised some capital
to buy Bitcoin.
I sold that offering
and decided not to invest because I
didn't really trust the management
because it's kind of meme stock and my
assumption is that the
you know, the management is part of the
formula for why it's a meme stock. So, I
didn't So, sort of meme stock, meme
management, didn't trust them and it
turned out it was that was a good call
in practice because they actually didn't
use Mhm. a lot of the money to buy
Bitcoin. And so of course, you know,
their investors were disappointed and
obviously I think that was a lost
opportunity for the company, but it
shows that
it's important to have confidence that
management actually are Bitcoiners, are
going to stay stay focused on Bitcoin
and are actually going to follow
through. Mhm. And you know, keep keep a
pace going as well. I think that's
another factor. When the money is big
enough, like it's a test for all these
management. Yeah, I mean, it's a funny
thing to say, but people say it's not
about the money, right? With Bitcoin.
And to some extent that's true because
you know, a lot of people are actually
focused on the bigger picture and the
longer term positive economic and
societal effects if Bitcoin continues to
grow, continues to get adoption
and provides the
you know, the world with a dependable
store of value where today it's actually
difficult to protect value.
You know, you have to if you just hold
cash or deposit account, you're probably
going to lose money inflation adjusted.
And so you're basically pushed to take
risk or to, you know,
give your money to investment managers
that try to protect you. So,
and that's effectively why you see
monetary premium
in in the stock market, in real estate,
in the bond market where arguably things
are overpriced Mhm. for what they
actually are in terms of their risk
return.
And so,
if Bitcoin eventually, you know, catches
up with gold, becomes a more established
and uh
larger store of value that people come
to depend on for preserving value over
the long term, preserving spending
power,
then I think that'll be positive. So, I
definitely see that in a lot of
Bitcoiners that they're really, you
know, philosophically interested in that
long-term outcome as a positive thing
for for humanity ultimately, right? So,
I think you can see that Michael Saylor
is quite enthusiastic. He puts a lot of
energy into talking about these far
future things and and a number of the
other treasury companies as well.
What is the end game? Let's say
most of the companies in the world now
holds Bitcoin.
And then what? Well, I mean, I think
that's that's probably where it's going
because
effectively, as I've said, Bitcoin is
the hurdle rate, which for
people who are familiar with invest like
hedge fund investments, they are
compensated with a management fee um and
then a success fee
or a carry, which is that they
uh get a percentage of the investment
return. Mhm. And um
now, they will also do a hurdle rate,
which is they won't, you know, if if you
can achieve 4% in a treasury bond and
they achieve 4%, they won't charge you
anything because you feel like you
shouldn't get charged for that baseline
easy to achieve rate. So, that's the
hurdle rate. And so,
by saying that Bitcoin is the hurdle
rate, basically saying if you look at
all investments compared to Bitcoin,
there's basically nothing that beat
Bitcoin in the last decade, right? Over
any given long-term period.
And so really, you know, the only way
for uh
a company or anybody to outperform
Bitcoin is to join Bitcoin. You know, I
mean, to to match it, you buy it.
>> Mhm. To outperform it, you you buy it
inside a company and you try to find
ways to increase the Bitcoin per share.
And so effectively, you could see a path
where
most companies have their treasury
in Bitcoin and then they're operating
their core business using excess profits
to, rather than to pay dividends or buy
back shares, to increase the Bitcoin per
share. Mhm. And you know, use some
capital to expand their business,
expand their products and services and
so forth. So, I think that could be
coming in the future and it's very
compatible with Bitcoin becoming a
long-term store of value that it would
make sense that companies are also using
that phenomenon.
I was talking to a gentleman here
yesterday. He is in the Bitcoin mining
space and we compared the
revenue of Bitcoin mining companies
versus Bitcoin treasury companies. And
well, the conclusion is it is easier
to go
the second route.
Well, if a lot of Bitcoin mining
companies do that, what does that How
does that affect Bitcoin network? The
mining is a kind of
uh commodity activity. So, if there's
if there's less hash rate because people
are buying Bitcoin instead of mining, it
will make mining more profitable. So
it's sort of self-correcting. You know,
if mining becomes more profitable then
they'll come back or new new entrants
will enter the mining space. Okay,
there's a favorite movie of yours. In
The Matrix, Neo wakes up and discover
that the system he thought was the
reality is actually a trap. And uh
Sailor quoted that and said, "Tickets to
escape The Matrix
are priced in Bitcoin."
Um Nice quote. Yeah.
What are we escaping?
And is it possible that one day we wake
up and realize there's another red pill
waiting for us? With Bitcoin, it tends
to have
not just a kind of passive, you know,
investment aspect, but
to change people's perspective to a
longer time frame. And there's kind of
long time preference concept.
Because ultimately
if you have a savings technology which
is
historically been very effective
it sort of incentivizes you to be less
consumerist and to save because you
know, if you save $1 today, maybe it
will become $10 or $100 in the future.
And actually within some period of time,
I think many people find themselves
re-denominating
the unit of account for their savings in
Bitcoin. So it's not or how many dollars
have I saved this year
you know, how's my savings portfolio
going in dollar terms, but how is it
going in Bitcoin terms? And so that
becomes a
um
I think actually a very good incentive
for people to think about the long term
because then they start planning for the
longer term, start thinking longer term,
so they're not trapped in the moment
in the you know, the 9-to-5
job
they're thinking about the future of
future future generation, families
and society ultimately. So I think it's
a healthier incentive back then. In
let's say a thousand years, people look
back and they see Adam back. How do you
want to be remembered? I like a mission,
a positive mission. So before Bitcoin I
was interested in
the Cypherpunks ideas, which are very
Bitcoin compatible ideas. So I'm kind of
long-term mission-focused person.
Um
So actually it's not about the money,
it's about a mission. And so you know, I
hope uh
hope the mission gets to its full
potential. What exactly is the mission?
Well, I think the mission is is sort of
about self-sovereignty and more
empowerment of the individual.
And ultimately, you know, uh a book I
like apart from that metrics on the film
side of things is Snow Crash, which is
sort of projecting the far future where
there's a much more free market
uh
environment in society and governments
are largely forgotten leftovers from the
previous era. We love you. Everybody
loves you. Um thank you for taking the
time. Of course. Thanks for having
>> Please please come back soon. All right.